SUZANA **BALBONA**

- suzybalbona212@yahoo.com
- 914-606-1707
- Scarsdale, NY 10583

SKILLS

- · Project multitasking
- Payroll and Benefits
- Recruitment and hiring
- Employee relations
- Microsoft Office proficiency
- · Relationship building
- HR Management Systems
- Event management
- Strategic planning
- Budgeting
- Operations management
- Policy development
- QuickBooks
- Expense reports
- TriNet
- Breezy
- ADP TotalSource
- LinkedIn Recruiter
- Slack

INDUSTRIES

- Healthcare
- Technology
- FinTech
- Crypto

EDUCATION

College of Mount Saint Vincent The Bronx, NY • 05/2010

Bachelor of Arts: Psychology

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Efficient and self-motivated HR/Administrative professional with the ability to effectively support business objectives and goals. Strong analytical, organizational, and problem-solving skills with the aptitude to work independently and adapt to changing environments. Experienced in a variety of HR and Operational functions including Recruitment, Compliance, Benefits Administration, Policy Formulation and Employee Relations.

WORK HISTORY

Hayward Recruiting - Talent Acquisition Consultant

Remote • 2/2023 - 2/2024

- -Assisted with 1099 Consulting for full time positions in Healthcare and IT
- -Managed full cycle recruitment for Engineering and RN roles
- -Partnered with Account Manager to understand job specifications and fill positions utilizing job boards and networking sites

Symbridge - HR & Talent Acquisition Manager

Greenwich, CT • 5/2021 - 2/2023 (Startup closed business)

- -Created innovative recruiting strategies using a variety of sourcing methods to attract talent
- -Partnered with leadership on staffing plans to effectively recruit and interview candidates
- -Aligned hiring practices with talent initiatives that enabled and supported diversity and inclusion
- -Leveraged Breezy to automate and streamline recruiting and hiring
- -Managed employment agency relationships including negotiating employment-related fees
- -Measured recruiting initiatives using qualitative and quantitative methods
- -Executed plans to drive productivity while achieving hiring goals
- -Conducted employment verifications, generated offer letters, and processed terminations
- -Prepared semimonthly payroll using ADP TotalSource

Accomplishments:

- -Successfully hired over 30 candidates across various functions and regions in IT, Operations, Sales, Marketing and Compliance
- -Implemented an employee referral program with incentives
- -Partnered with the executive team to initiate a summer internship program with defined projects and goals for the Sales department

Ignite Recruitment - Talent Acquisition Lead

Remote • 10/2019 - 5/2021

- -Managed multiple full cycle recruiting processes simultaneously for permanent positions in a variety of different industries
- -Worked directly with Account Manager to understand job specifications and qualifications for effective recruitment
- -Screened candidates to fill open roles utilizing sources including job boards, professional networking sites and referrals
- -Managed client and candidate expectations including compensation and benefits negotiation during offer process

Ayehu Inc. - HR & Operations Manager

New York, NY • 05/2016 - 10/2019

- -Managed all office operations and procedures
- -Ensured all PO's were invoiced in a timely manner using QuickBooks
- -Maintained domestic and international business trips for staff
- -Responded to incoming correspondences related to HR and employee matters
- -Worked with hiring managers to lead recruitment for open roles and handled on-boarding process
- -Managed administrative HR components including posting job ads, contacting candidates, conducting interviews, preparing offer letters and processing new hire paperwork
- -Conducted employment verifications, managed separation letters and processed terminations
- -Prepared semimonthly payroll and handled benefits administration
- -Maintained employee files, implemented salary increases and administered commission in accordance

Accomplishments:

- -Initiated 401K plan and an annual Performance Review program
- -Saved external agency recruitment fees through direct sourcing for technical and sales positions

VMTurbo - Operations Administrator

Valhalla, NY • 03/2015 - 10/2015

- -Assisted with HR functions including on-boarding of new hires
- -Assisted with off boarding employees including processing of terminations
- -Administered new hire paperwork and entered all employees in the E-Verify system
- -Managed an accurate filing system for all active and terminated employees
- -Worked with the Talent Acquisition department in Boston to coordinate on-site interviews
- -Ordered office supplies/equipment
- -Worked with the Director of Human Resources to organize executive conferences and networking events
- -Facilitated travel arrangements for candidates and employees

Smith Arnold Partners - Information Technology Recruiter Stamford, CT • 11/2013 - 08/2014

- -Effectively identified the most qualified candidates for clients in the New York metropolitan area
- -Maintained a network through internet sources and referrals while utilizing an applicant tracking system
- -Sourced candidates in mid-high level IT positions while meeting the expectations and requirements of the client
- -Assisted candidates with resume building and interviewing techniques by providing prep videos and documents with detailed information on the company
- -Developed and implemented a constructive screening process to ensure that each candidate was placed in an opportunity that best fit their background